<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>virt on longoconsulting.us</title>
    <link>https://drizuid.github.io/categories/virt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in virt on longoconsulting.us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 17:51:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://drizuid.github.io/categories/virt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Routing containers through Wireguard</title>
      <link>https://drizuid.github.io/2024/03/routing-containers-through-wireguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 17:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drizuid.github.io/2024/03/routing-containers-through-wireguard/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I show how I went about getting transmission to work through wireguard while still being able to have my other applications properly interface with transmission.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Authentik as an identity provider</title>
      <link>https://drizuid.github.io/2023/02/using-authentik-as-an-identity-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drizuid.github.io/2023/02/using-authentik-as-an-identity-provider/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the linuxserver.io secure web access gateway (SWAG) coupled with Authelia as my identity provider for quite some time. It works extremely well and I&amp;rsquo;ve been very pleased not only with the application itself, but also with the support from the authelia devs. That said, there are some features I wish authelia had that they do not yet. The biggest feature is SAML support. As many of you know, I focus heavily on Cisco Unified Communications. Cisco UC supports SAML SSO and I haven&amp;rsquo;t had anything in my lab that would let me tinker with this. Authentik can do everything authelia does plus some extras, which include SAML. I will say that I am typing this as I wing setting it up and I can already see that authentik is not as simple to configure/deploy as authelia. As a note, since I am documenting this as I do it, I will include any mistakes and how i resolve those mistakes. This is my first time touching authentik and I am purely going off the documentation available at &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://goauthentik.io/docs/&#34;&gt;https://goauthentik.io/docs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PC for my kids update3</title>
      <link>https://drizuid.github.io/2022/09/pc-for-my-kids-update3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 14:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drizuid.github.io/2022/09/pc-for-my-kids-update3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been quite some years since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.longoconsulting.us/2017/01/pc-for-my-kids/&#34;&gt;original build&lt;/a&gt; and even the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.longoconsulting.us/2018/02/pc-for-my-kids-update/&#34;&gt;follow-up rebuild&lt;/a&gt;. The original build was when my oldest (turning 13) was 7 and my middle child (turning 10) was 4. They&amp;rsquo;ve had the same AMD R7 240 graphics cards since then. Unfortunately, the games they play which began as browser based games and minecraft, have upgraded to things like roblox, fortnite, and somehow minecraft&amp;rsquo;s blocks needs more juice. So here we are. Over labor day, my friend (thanks &lt;strong&gt;@ctark&lt;/strong&gt;) pointed a sale at antonline out to me where they had RTX 2060&amp;rsquo;s in stock for 224$ each. First, I&amp;rsquo;ve not seen a graphics card in stock for a long time and second, while 224$ is well over what I might have planned to do for them, I thought it was worth it. Just looking at benchmarks, the new card is effectively &lt;a href=&#34;https://gpu.userbenchmark.com/Compare/Nvidia-RTX-2060-vs-AMD-R7-240/4034vsm8608&#34;&gt;almost 1500% better&lt;/a&gt;, so I decided to jump in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 with docker containers</title>
      <link>https://drizuid.github.io/2022/01/ipv6-with-docker-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 17:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drizuid.github.io/2022/01/ipv6-with-docker-containers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since my last post, but I wanted to cover something I had tinkered with a few times and finally got to a state I&amp;rsquo;m ok with. IPv6 in docker containers. For my testing, I will be using linuxserver.io containers, as being part of the team allows me to easily fix anything that prevents full functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I guess to start, a big thing I found is most ipv6 guides, including the official documentation, tells you how to enable ipv6 for the default bridge. As we all know, the default bridge is trash, it doesnt work like a custom bridge and causes a number of issues. You may also see guides that lead you to setup nds proxy which works, but it introduces a HUGE amount of latency. When I tested the NDS proxy method, i couldn&amp;rsquo;t stand how slow it was and quickly reverted the change. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get into how I set it up, note that I am not claiming to have the best method, the most efficient method, the most secure method or anything of the sort. This is just how I set it up to get what I wanted working in a way I was OK with.&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.longoconsulting.us/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/dockernet-blog-1024x492.png&#34; alt=&#34;This is a graphic I made to help users understand bridge networks. Many thought it was alien, but this shows that most users do this same thing today with port forwarding on their router.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When you need a server to tackle tasks</title>
      <link>https://drizuid.github.io/2019/06/when-you-need-a-server-to-tackle-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 20:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drizuid.github.io/2019/06/when-you-need-a-server-to-tackle-tasks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when you’re in a client environment, you just need something you don’t have access to. That could be NTP, DNS, gateways, an internal CA, or even just an SFTP server. I encounter this all the time and my solution is almost always to simply get an IP from the client and spin up a linux server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I decided to make this a vLog entry rather than a blog, so please check out the videos. I would like to point out that the part2 video does have an error in the alt_names section for the IP address. DNS entries are prepended by DNS: but ip addresses are prepended by IP: In my video, I prepended the IP with DNS: this will not work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PC for my kids update</title>
      <link>https://drizuid.github.io/2018/02/pc-for-my-kids-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drizuid.github.io/2018/02/pc-for-my-kids-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See the original post, PC for my kids, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.longoconsulting.us/2017/01/pc-for-my-kids/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll start off with the bad news. After the two win10 vms were running perfectly for over a year now, I was running updates on my other linux servers… some how i did pay attention and upgraded the distro of my kvm box. It pretty much ruined everything, now I get stuck at the windows logo during boot. I even tried simply reinstalling the vm guest, but when the kvm booted from the win10 iso, it would freeze at… you guessed it, the windows logo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PC for my kids</title>
      <link>https://drizuid.github.io/2017/01/pc-for-my-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drizuid.github.io/2017/01/pc-for-my-kids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little background. I have a 7 and 4 year old who like playing on the computer. Typically they play things like animaljam or nickjr games, very simple requirements, minimal hardware needs. One day, the horror that is minecraft crept its way into my home and suddenly, graphics (seriously? in minecraft, it&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of blocks…) mattered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
