<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New home on longoconsulting.us</title>
    <link>https://drizuid.github.io/tags/new-home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New home on longoconsulting.us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 16:08:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://drizuid.github.io/tags/new-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Additional notes for ATT xgs-pon bypass</title>
      <link>https://drizuid.github.io/2023/03/additional-notes-for-att-xgs-pon-bypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 16:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drizuid.github.io/2023/03/additional-notes-for-att-xgs-pon-bypass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I posted about swapping to 2G service which would move me from alt-optic gpon to xgs-pon and then allow me to fully bypass the ATT ont and not even use 802.11x configuration. I thought it was pretty detailed, but I was asked about some of the outputs during the setup. Fortunately, I kept the notes in my notepad instance and can expand on things. This is an addendum to the original article &lt;a href=&#34;https://drizuid.github.io/2023/03/moving-to-opnsense-and-2gbps-internet/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Home – New Network</title>
      <link>https://drizuid.github.io/2021/03/new-home-new-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 23:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drizuid.github.io/2021/03/new-home-new-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING: This post has a lot of pictures!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write this up for a while, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been lazy/busy. As some may know, I relocated with my family from Nashville to Kentucky when my wife accepted her new position. As a consultant, I have the freedom to live and work from anywhere, so moving to improve my wife&amp;rsquo;s career was no big deal. Fortunately, a new home offers the chance to correct oversights on the last one. One of the first things I did was take the plans and determine how I wanted my network to look. I knew I wanted a collapsed core with access layer devices on each floor. I started by estimating how many wired connections per floor I would want. After this, I segmented those out to determine how many needed POE. The biggest thing was ensuring I left room for growth. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.longoconsulting.us/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/rack-design-1024x701.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
