<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>womp on longoconsulting.us</title>
    <link>/categories/womp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in womp on longoconsulting.us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 16:11:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/womp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving to OPNsense and 2Gbps Internet</title>
      <link>/2023/03/moving-to-opnsense-and-2gbps-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 16:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2023/03/moving-to-opnsense-and-2gbps-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning on doing this transition for a bit, but I wanted to get things in place and ensure I had a solid plan before executing. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss what I had, my plan, and what I moved to here a bit. If any of you have read my previous post, &lt;a href=&#34;/2020/01/att-uverse-rg-bypass/&#34;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T Uverse RG Bypass&lt;/a&gt;, then you know I am a big fan of bypassing the ATT provided RG to use my own equipment. With my 1000/1000 service, the fiber (alt optic unfortunately) came into the ATT ONT, directly to my router (initially ERL3, later ER4) which then went to my core switch to my access switches. The plan initially began to form because rather than faking the 802.1x on my router, I could instead use my own ONT and fully bypass everything ATT had in my home. Some people can do this with GPON 1G or less service, but in the former bellsouth areas, we had alt optic which uses a 1550nm wavelength rather than 1490nm wavelength, so the GPON bypass wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible for me. My plan was to get a 2.5G+ capable router with sufficient disk, memory, and cpu to handle routing at whatever speed I went with. I ordered two devices: A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliexpress.us/item/3256803996127706.html&#34;&gt;GW-R86S-G2&lt;/a&gt;, and an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliexpress.us/item/3256804448843528.html&#34;&gt;N6005/4xi226-V&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.longoconsulting.us/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/diagram-1024x149.png&#34; alt=&#34;network diagram&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A sad day.</title>
      <link>/2020/05/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 01:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/05/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know, I&amp;rsquo;ve documented my IT adventures for over 5 years now. Personally, I think a lot of my articles were pretty useful and I actually referenced them regularly while working on client systems. Sadly, today I had a database failure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T Uverse RG Bypass</title>
      <link>/2020/01/att-uverse-rg-bypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 02:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/01/att-uverse-rg-bypass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the data loss, all text was lost but images remain. I will try to add the text later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Something about 8192 NAT table limitation here, if that doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother you, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to proceed unless you want to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.longoconsulting.us/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/standard.png&#34; alt=&#34;Standard Setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRASH! Getting root on Cisco UC Devices without TAC!</title>
      <link>/2019/09/root-access-on-cisco-uc-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2019/09/root-access-on-cisco-uc-devices/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: Due to poor backups, I lost this post. I was able to restore it thanks to the Internet Archive, but I lost all images. I will try to restore these at a later time.&#xA;I was working with a client and we were doing a parallel build in their environment. To do this, i build the new environment without vnics connected, then i disconnected production and connected the new. However, we ran into some issues and had to revert.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
